"!" and "?" at the end of method names

name = "sample_string"
name.reverse
name.reverse!
name.is_binary_data?

"Sugarcoating" for readability, but they do have common meanings:

• Methods ending in ! perform some permanent or potentially dangerous change; for example:
 • Enumerable#sort returns a sorted version of the object while Enumerable#sort! sorts it in place.
 • In Rails, ActiveRecord::Base#save returns false if saving failed, while ActiveRecord::Base#save! raises an exception.
 • Kernel::exit causes a script to exit, while Kernel::exit! does so immediately, bypassing any exit handlers.

• Methods ending in ? return a boolean, which makes the code flow even more intuitively like a sentence — if number.zero? reads like "if the number is zero", but if number.zero just looks weird.

In your example, name.reverse evaluates to a reversed string, but only after the name.reverse! line does the name variable actually contain the reversed name. name.is_binary_data? looks like "is name binary data?".
